Harvard University. Corporation. Records of land and property owned by Harvard University, 1643-1835: an inventory
Records of land and property owned by Harvard University, 1643-1835
- VII. Maine / "Eastern lands," 1690-1835, 1.62 cubic feet (2.5 document boxes and 23 oversize folders)
  - I. Bucksport, 1801-1835
    - John Davis’ agreement with Moses Stubbs regarding Bucksport land, Dec. 18, 1818, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 83
    - Letter from Samuel M. Pond to John Davis requesting a deed to Bucksport land for Reuben Stubbs, July 22, 1819, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 84
    - Plan of College land in Bucksport, June 15, 1819, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 85
    - Letter from Caleb Hall to John Davis about Bucksport lot, Sept. 1, 1819, with plan of lot drawn by surveyor James Grant, Jr., UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 86
    - Memorandum regarding Moses Stubbs and Reuben Stubbs’ claims to Bucksport land, Nov. 22, 1819?, UAI 15.750 Box 8, Folder 14
    - Letter from Samuel M. Pond to John Davis, Dec. 25, 1819?, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 87
    - Samuel Little’s affidavit regarding Bucksport land, Dec. 25, 1819, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 88
    - Reuben Stubb’s affidavit regarding Bucksport land, Dec. 25, 1819, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 89
    - Samuel Little’s petition regarding Bucksport land, ca. 1819, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 90
    - Statement from Reuben Stubbs concerning Samuel Little’s claim of Bucksport land, May 5, 1820, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 91
    - Letter from Samuel M. Pond to John Davis and accompanying affidavit from Nehemiah Rich concerning Bucksport land, May 26, 1820, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 92
    - Memoranda from John Davis concerning Reuben Stubbs’ right to a deed for Bucksport land and the extent of his lot, Oct. 26, 1820 and undated, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 93
    - Letters from Reuben Stubbs to John Davis, Nov. 2, 1821 and Dec. 17, 1821, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 94
    - Appraisal of Bucksport land by Samuel M. Pond, Abner Curtis, and Joshua Howe, July 1822 and memorandum about the land (verso), Sept. 25, 1824, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 95
    - Reuben Stubbs receipt for payment to John Davis, Sept. 25, 1824, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 96
    - Letter from Joseph Tuckerman to John Davis, Sept. 25, 1824?, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 97
      Tuckerman found a document belonging to Davis in a book “in Mr. Hall’s book store,” and returned it to him, with this letter.
    - Memorandum about Bucksport land, Nov. 24, 1824?, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 1
    - Letter from Samuel M. Pond to Josiah Quincy about Bucksport land, Aug. 5, 1834, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 2
    - Letter from Samuel M. Pond to H. Story about Bucksport land, Sept. 10, 1834, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 3
    - Thomas Wren Ward’s memorandum about Bucksport land, Aug. 1835, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 4
  - J. Sullivan, 1802-1817
    Records in this subseries pertain to Harvard-owned land in Sullivan and include correspondence and a memorandum.
    - Eliphalet Pearson’s notes about College lands in Sullivan, ca. 1802, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 5
    - Letter from Paul Dudley Sargent to Samuel Webber about College lands in Sullivan, Sept. 15, 1809, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 6
    - Memorandum about Sullivan lots, June 12, 1810, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 7
      Addendum on verso lists applicants to purchase land, 1815.
    - Letter from John Preble to John Davis about Sullivan land, July 10, 1815, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 8
    - Letters from Melatiah Jordan to John Davis about the division of the Sullivan lots, July 27, 1816 and Feb. 14, 1817, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 9
  - K. Correspondence with Prentiss Mellen, 1808-1827
    This subseries contains correspondence with Massachusetts senator and Chief Justice of the Supreme Court of Maine, Prentiss Mellen, who served as a land agent in Maine for Harvard from 1808 to 1827. Included are charts documenting the various lots belonging to Harvard, as well as charts listing the lands both sold and unsold by Mellen. The bulk of the records are letters from Mellen to Harvard Treasurer John Davis.
    - Chart listing grants of Maine lands to Harvard College, and memorandum about lands appraised, March 1808?, UAI 15.750 Box 9, Folder 4
    - Manuscript copy of letter from Jonathan Jackson to Prentiss Mellen with detailed instructions, and supplementary descriptions of individual lots, April 27, 1809, UAI 15.750 Box 8, Folder 15
    - Manuscript copies of chart listing grants of Maine lands to Harvard College made between 1762 and 1785, sent to Prentiss Mellen in April 1809, UAI 15.750 Box 9, Folders 5 and 6
      Charts include the following information about each parcel of land: date it was granted, donor, location, size, number of lots, and name of its township and county.
    - Chart listing grants of Maine lands to Harvard College made between 1762 and 1785, as well as lands drawn in the 1787 lottery, sent to General Cobb in April 1809, UAI 15.750 Oversize Cabinet, Folder 2
      Includes the following information about each parcel of land: date it was granted, donor, location, size, number of lots, and name of its township and county.
    - Draft of chart listing grants of Maine lands to Harvard College made between 1762 and 1785, ca. April 1809?, UAI 15.750 Box 9, Folder 7
      This chart appears to have been a preparatory one, used in the creation of similar charts in April 1809.
    - Chart listing grants of Maine lands to Harvard College made between 1762 and 1785, compiled ca. April 1809?, UAI 15.750 Box 9, Folder 8
    - Chart listing grants of Maine lands to Harvard College made between 1762 and 1785, compiled from the General Court records of James Winthrop, ca. April 1809?, UAI 15.750 Box 9, Folder 9
    - Memoranda regarding lands in Maine, compiled ca. April 1809?, UAI 15.750 Box 9, Folder 10
    - Chart of Maine lands granted to Harvard by the General Court between 1759 and 1774, compiled ca. April 1809 (4 copies), UAI 15.750 Box 9, Folder 11
    - Memorandum concerning history and appraisal of College lands in Maine, compiled ca. April 1809?, UAI 15.750 Box 9, Folder 12
      Includes information about Lothrop Lewis’ appraisal of several lots.
    - Memoranda about Prentiss Mellen’s compensation and Harvard’s agreement to cover all appraisal costs, Aug. 25, 1809, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 10
    - Harvard Corporation vote about Prentiss Mellen, Sept. 5, 1809, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 11
    - Letters from Prentiss Mellen to Jonathan Jackson, Sept. 7, 1809 and Sept. 12, 1809, and draft of reply to Mellen written by Jackson’s son, Sept. 15, 1809, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 12
    - Lothrop Lewis’ appraisal of College lands in Paris, Otisfield, Harrison, Turner, Poland, Lovell, Baldwin, Brownfield, Rumford, Jay, Wilton, New Sharon, and Raymond, Nov. 1809, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 13
    - Letter from Prentiss Mellen to Jonathan Jackson about sale of New Sharon lot, Dec. 23, 1809, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 14
    - Letter from Jonathan Jackson to Prentiss Mellen about sale of New Sharon lot, Dec. 27, 1809, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 15
    - Statement of Prentiss Mellen’s account with Harvard College, July 1809-Jan. 1810, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 16
    - Letter from Prentiss Mellen to Jonathan Jackson about sale of Lovell land to John McMillan, Jan. 5, 1810 and copy of McMillan’s notes for the land, Jan. 17, 1810, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 17
    - Letter from Prentiss Mellen to Samuel Webber, March 24, 1810, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 18
    - Letters from Prentiss Mellen to John Davis regarding land sales, April 10, 1810; April 13, 1810; July 20, 1810; Aug. 21, 1810; and Sept. 3, 1810, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 19
    - Letters from Prentiss Mellen to John Davis regarding William Bradford’s purchase of Turner lot, Jan. 9, 1811; Jan. 16, 1811; and Feb. 17, 1811, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 20
    - Letters from Prentiss Mellen to John Davis about land sales, Aug. 24, 1811; Sept. 13, 1811; Nov. 14, 1811; and Dec. 30, 1811, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 21
    - Letters from Prentiss Mellen to John Davis about land sales, Feb. 3, 1812; Feb. 28, 1812; and March 27, 1812, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 22
    - Memorandum from John Kirkland about land sales, April 16, 1812, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 23
    - Letters from Prentiss Mellen to John Davis about land sales, July 14, 1812; July 18, 1812; Nov. 10, 1812; and Dec. 28, 1812, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 24
    - Letters from Prentiss Mellen to John Davis about land sales, Feb. 20, 1813; June 25, 1813; July 14, 1813; July 21, 1813; and Aug. 25, 1813, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 25
    - Letters from Prentiss Mellen to John Davis about land sales, Aug. 26, 1813; Sept. 13, 1813; Oct. 19, 1813; and Nov. 12, 1813, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 26
    - Letters from Prentiss Mellen to John Davis about land sales, Jan. 5, 1814; Jan. 6, 1814; Jan. 10, 1814; Jan. 26, 1814; and Feb. 9, 1814, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 27
    - Letters from Prentiss Mellen to John Davis about land sales, March 4, 1814; March 22, 1814; March 22, 1814; April 26, 1814; May 26, 1814; and July 5, 1814, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 28
    - Letters from Prentiss Mellen to John Davis about land sales, July 18, 1814; July 21, 1814; July 29, 1814; Aug. 1, 1814; and Aug. 5, 1814, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 29
    - Letters from Prentiss Mellen to John Davis about land sales, Oct. 14, 1814; Nov. 24, 1814; Jan. 16, 1815; and May 2, 1815, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 30
    - Letters from Prentiss Mellen to John Davis about land sales, Feb. 5, 1816; May 16, 1816; Aug. 31, 1816; Oct. 15, 1816; and Nov. 12, 1816, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 31
    - Letter from Prentiss Mellen to John Davis about land sales, Dec. 18, 1816, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 32
    - Letters from Prentiss Mellen to John Davis about land sales, Dec. 28, 1816; Jan. 17, 1817; Feb. 13, 1817; Feb. 19, 1817; and April 18, 1817, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 33
    - Schedule of College lands in Maine sold by Prentiss Mellen, May 3, 1817, UAI 15.750 Box 9, Folder 13
      This large chart and includes the names of land purchasers; the size, number, and location of the lots; and the price, among other information.
    - Letters from Prentiss Mellen to John Davis about land sales, May 5, 1817; July 8, 1818; Aug. 19, 1819; June 26, 1820; and July 7, 1820, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 34
    - Letters from Prentiss Mellen to John Davis about land sales, Nov. 3, 1820; Feb. 21, 1821; June 26, 1821; and Jan. 25, 1822, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 35
    - Letters from Grenville Mellen to John Davis, March 18, 1822 and March 22, 1822, and receipt for payment, March 18, 1822?, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 36
      Grenville Mellen was Prentiss Mellen’s son.
    - Letters from Prentiss Mellen to John Davis about land sales, March 22, 1822; June 13, 1822; July 23, 1822; Dec. 10, 1822; and March 14, 1823, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 37
    - Letters from Prentiss Mellen to John Davis about land sales, May 16, 1823; Oct. 9, 1823; Nov. 27, 1823; March 5, 1825; and July 1, 1826, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 38
    - Account book: Prentiss Mellen’s account with Harvard College 1810-1827, through Feb. 1, 1827, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 39
      This is a slim paper-bound book created by Mellen and sent to Davis with Mellen’s letter of March 20, 1827
    - Letter from Prentiss Mellen to John Davis about land sales, March 20, 1827, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 40
    - Letter from John Davis to Prentiss Mellen about land sales, March 27, 1827, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 41
    - Letters from Prentiss Mellon to John Davis about land sales, March 29, 1827; Oct. 19, 1827; and Nov. 2, 1827, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 42
    - Account of College lands in Maine sold by Prentiss Mellen, as well as unsold lands, ca. Nov. 1827, UAI 15.750 Oversize cabinet, Folder 3
    - Schedule of College lands in Maine sold by Prentiss Mellen, as well as unsold lands, March 20, 1827?, UAI 15.750 Box 9, Folder 14
    - Calculations related to Prentiss Mellen’s account with Harvard College, undated, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 43
  - L. Land Auction, 1832-1835
    Records in this subseries concern a land auction held on August 5, 1835, in which Harvard attempted to sell its remaining land holdings in Maine. The auctioneers were Whitwell, Bond Co., and the lands for sale were those left unsold by Prentiss Mellen, as well as a lot of one half of a township referred to as "Township No. 3, 8th range." This lot had been granted by the Commonwealth of Massachusetts to the Trustees of the Massachusetts Society for Promoting Agriculture on Feb. 21, 1829, "for the support and maintenance of the Massachusetts professorship of Natural History." The land was presumably transferred to Harvard, and was successfully sold at the auction. This subseries contains correspondence, a deed of conveyance, a surveyor's plan, copies of the deeds of sale for each lot, an auction handbill, sales agreements, and memoranda.
    - Letter from B. R. Nichols to Thomas Wren Ward about unsold land in Maine, June 11, 1832, with memorandum about Lottery lands, ca. 1832?, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 44
    - Memorandum about Maine lands sold by Ebenezer Francis and Thomas Wren Ward, compiled after Jan. 23, 1835, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 45
    - Manuscript copy of deed of conveyance of Maine land, George W. Coffin to the Trustees of the Massachusetts Society for Promoting Agriculture, Feb. 13, 1835, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 46
    - Letter from Joseph L. Kelsey to George W. Coffin about his survey of Maine land, April 15, 1835 and the enclosed survey and related notes, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 47
      Related to Township No. 3, 8th range.
    - Sketch of Maine lot in Township No. 3, 8th range, created by surveyor Joseph L. Kelsey, April 1835, UAI 15.750 Box 9, Folder 15
    - Manuscript copy of handbill and advertisement for auction of remaining Maine lands, June 24, 1835, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 48
    - Auction handbill: “Sale of Eastern Lands,” June 24, 1835 (2 copies), UAI 15.750 Box 8, Folder 16
    - Letter from Anson G. Chandler to Josiah Quincy, July 11, 1835, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 49
      Chandler wrote to inform Quincy that one of the lots the College was advertising to be sold in the auction had already been sold, in January 1825. It was subsequently removed from the auction list.
    - Letter from John Dudley about the value of land in Township No. 3, 8th range, July 20, 1835, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 50
    - Letter from Thomas Freeman to Whitwell, Bond Co., July 27, 1835, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 51
    - Memorandum regarding unsold College lands in Maine and lottery lands, July 1835, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 52
    - Josephus Chandler’s description of his exploration of Township No. 3, 8th range, Aug. 4, 1835, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 53
    - Letter from Thomas Wren Ward to Whitwell, Bond Co. about the auction, Aug. 4, 1835, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 54
      Ward explained that Township No. 3, 8th range was also to be sold in the upcoming auction.
    - Sale agreement of land in Township No. 3, 8th range, signed by both parties on Aug. 5, 1835, and manuscript copy of deed, Aug. 5, 1835, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 55
      The lot at Township No. 3, 8th range was sold at the auction to James Hobart and Seth Bryant.
    - Sale agreements for auctioned Maine lands, signed by purchasers and Harvard Treasurer Thomas Wren Ward, Aug. 5, 1835, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folders 56-59
    - Manuscript copies of deeds for Maine lands sold at auction, Aug. 5, 1835, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 60
    - Statements of account, Whitwell, Bond Co. with Harvard College, Aug. 22, 1835, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 61
    - Memorandum about sale of remaining Maine lands, by Thomas Wren Ward, Aug. 31, 1835, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 62
      This memo appears to have previously functioned as a wrapper for all the documents in this series.
    - Two documents with calculations related to auction of Maine lands, ca. 1835, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 63
- VIII. Newton, 1704-1812, .09 cubic feet (3 legal folders and 3 oversize folders)
  The records in this series concern two lots of land in Newton, Massachusetts (previously called Cambridge) given to Harvard College. Relatively little is known about these lots. One lot, of about 40 acres "near the falls on Charles River," was given by Richard Champney in 1669 or 1672 (sources differ), "as an expression of his willingness to further the education of youth in all godly literature." It is not clear who donated the other lot, a piece of land which was "twenty seven acres three roods thirty two rods" in size. Records include surveyors' plans of the two lots, leases of the lots, and a receipt related to the Harvard Treasurer's records of the sale of one of the lots.
  - Plan of Newton lot (40 acres) given to Harvard by Richard Champney, drawn by surveyor David Fisk(?) in 1704, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 64
  - Lease of Newton lot (40 acres) to Nathaniel Hubbard for ninety-nine years beginning March 25, 1705, created and signed March 25, 1713, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 65
    Signed by Nathaniel Hubbard, Henry Flynt, and Peter Oliver. Contains indications of payments received, 1714-1740.
  - Lease of Lot 33 in Newton to Jonathan Willard, March 25, 1726, UAI 15.750 Box 8, Folder 17
    Signed by Edward Hutchinson, John Corssen, and Thomas Coverly. A small note, which was formerly pinned to this lease but has now been detached, concerns land in Newton as well as land in Menotomy.
  - Plan of Newton land (“twenty seven acres three roods thirty two rods”) drawn by surveyor Abraham Fuller, Sept. 19, 1765, UAI 15.750 Box 8, Folder 18
  - Plan of Newton land (“39 acres and 15 rods”) drawn by surveyor Abraham Fuller, Sept. 19, 1765, UAI 15.750 Box 8, Folder 19
  - Isaac Fiske’s receipt for borrowing papers related to sale of land in Newton, Oct. 24, 1812, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 66
    The land in Newton was sold to Ephraim Jackson, and Fiske apparently borrowed papers related to the sale from Treasurer John Davis.
- IX. Rutland, 1718-1793, .18 cubic feet (10 legal folders and 4 oversize folders)
  Records in this series pertain to a 250 acre lot in Rutland, Massachusetts given to Harvard College by the Proprietors of the Town of Rutland in 1718. The records include a copy of the Proprietors' vote to award the land to Harvard; correspondence with tenants William Browning and Samuel Browning; several plans of the College lot, drawn by surveyors Thomas Harman and Thomas Hale, Jr.; and a June 27, 1793 agreement to sell the lot to Benjamin Joslyn for £250.
  - Vote of Proprietors of the town of Rutland to give a lot to Harvard College, Nov. 5, 1718, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 67
  - Plan of town of Rutland, 1718, UAI 15.750 Box 8, Folder 20
  - Edward Holyoke’s memorandum about hiring Thomas Harman to survey the Rutland farm, May 28, 1751, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 68
    Holyoke indicates that he plans to “give the refusal of the lease” of the East part of the farm to William and James Browning, i.e. allow them to lease the land, if they so choose, before offering it to anyone else.
  - Plan of Rutland land drawn by surveyor Thomas Harman, June 10-11, 1751, UAI 15.750 Box 8, Folder 21
    Harman notes that John Lamond and Robert Lamond were his chain-men during the survey. Verso of plan is heavily annotated and includes a memorandum about William Browning’s offer to purchase the land in 1753.
  - Letter from Thomas Harman to Edward Holyoke about Rutland land, June 19, 1751, UAI 15.750 Box 8, Folder 22
  - Letter from Thomas Frink to Edward Holyoke, testifying about the good character of William and James Browning, June 21, 1751, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 69
  - Letter from Thomas Harman to Edward Holyoke about Rutland land, including his bill for survey work, July 2, 1751, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 70
  - Letter from William Browning and Samuel Browning to Ebenezer Storer about Rutland land, March 10, 1780, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 71
    The brothers mistakenly wrote “Story” rather than “Storer.” Letter refers to the land being “run up since the [Revolutionary] War begun” and in need of repairs.
  - Letter from William Browning and Samuel Browning to Ebenezer Storer about Rutland land, April 17, 1780, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 72
  - Letter from William Browning to Ebenezer Storer about Rutland land, March 15, 1787 and draft of Storer’s response, March 29, 1787, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 73
    Apparently someone had spread a rumor about Browning to Storer, and Browning wrote to set the record straight. He had been accused of being “one of Shayes’s Confederates,” i.e. a participant in Shays’ Rebellion, but claimed he was innocent. Storer appears to have believed him.
  - Letter from William Browning to Ebenezer Storer about Rutland land, Jan. 5, 1789, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 74
  - Plan of College land in Rutland, drawn by surveyor Thomas Hale, Jr., Nov. 22, 1792, UAI 15.750 Box 8, Folder 23
    The land is described here as being in Oakham.
  - Ebenezer Storer’s agreement to sell Rutland land to Benjamin Joslyn, June 27, 1793, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 75
    Verso contains annotations of payment, as well as a note indicating that a deed for the land was delivered to Joslyn upon his last payment, made Jan. 16, 1795 (incorrectly written 1794). In total, he paid £250 for the land.
  - Plan of Rutland land, undated, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 76
- X. Framingham (Danforth Estate), 1698-1779, .10 cubic feet (4 legal folders and 3 oversize folders)
  Thomas Danforth (1623-1699), who served as Treasurer of Harvard College from 1650 to 1658 and as Steward from 1668 to 1682, had very sizable land holdings in Framingham, Massachusetts (formerly referred to as "Danforth's Farm.") He bequeathed multiple lots there to Harvard, stipulating that rental income from the tenants to whom he had awarded very long leases (999 years) should be paid to the College after his death. By providing such long leases at a low cost, Danforth encouraged settlement in Framingham. Although he died in 1699, it appears to have taken some time for Harvard to have received any financial benefit from his bequest. Tenants John Whitney and Moses Haven were informed by 1726 that they should thenceforward pay their rents to the Harvard Treasurer. Later tenants included Isaac Bowin and Benjamin Whitney, who would eventually transfer their leases to Daniel Haven. Harvard eventually sold the lots, to Moses Haven and Daniel Haven in 1767, and to Nathaniel Biglow at an unknown date. This series includes leases and other records related to multiple lots.
  - Lease of multiple lots in Framingham for 999 years, Thomas Danforth to Isaac Bowen, March 25, 1698 (signed by Bowen), UAI 15.750 Oversize cabinet, Folder 4
    Gift of Charles H. Taylor: Dec. 2, 1924.
    Signed by Isaac Bowen in the presence of Josiah Parker, John Whiting, and John Fiske. Multiple lots were included in the lease, totaling 58+ acres. Danforth died the year after this lease was signed and bequeathed the lands and rents to Harvard. Verso indicates that Edward Holyoke sold the land to Moses Haven on Aug. 11, 1767, on behalf of the Harvard Corporation.
  - Lease of multiple lots in Framingham for 999 years, Thomas Danforth to Isaac Bowen, March 25, 1698 (signed by Danforth), UAI 15.750 Oversize cabinet, Folder 5
    Signed by Thomas Danforth in the presence of Josiah Parker, John Whiting, and John Fiske. Verso contains annotations from 1702 and other years, some of them difficult to read.
  - Lease of multiple lots in Framingham for 999 years, Thomas Danforth to John Whitney, March 25, 1699, UAI 15.750 Oversize cabinet, Folder 6